Now assume there is a car that is totally lost,
では 車が完全に道に迷った つまり運転者または車として
which means you, as a driver or as a car,
どこにいるのか 手がかりがない
have no clue where you are.
と仮定します
Now you assume that you have a global map of the environment.
そしてその環境のグローバルマップ を持っていると仮定します
In this example, you can see a map
この例では [サニーベール]
of the environment around the [INAUDIBLE] office
にある[メルセデス]オフィスの 辺りの環境の
in [INAUDIBLE].
マップを見られます
Now, generally speaking, localization
一般的に言うと ローカライゼーションでは
answers a question, where is our car in a given
与えられた地図において 高精度でどこに車がいるのか
map with a high accuracy?
という質問に答えます
And high accuracy means between three and 10 centimeters.
そして高精度とは 3～10 センチのことをいいます
In a traditional way, we use global navigation satellite
従来の方法では 全地球的航法衛星システムを
systems to find the car, with respect to the map.
使用して地図に対して 車を検索します
But GPS is not precise enough.
ただ GPS は十分な精度ではありません
Most of the time, GPS has an accuracy
多くの場合 GPS は 1 車線
of the worth of a lane-- about one to three meters.
つまり約 1～3 メートル に値する精度があります
But sometimes it can be as broad as 10 to 50 meters.
場合によっては 10～50 メートルの広さのこともあります
Clearly this is not reliable enough for a self-driving car.
明らかにこれでは 自動運転車にとっては信頼性が不十分です
So you can't trust GPS.
ですから GPS を信頼できません
And you have to find another technique to localize yourself
与えられたマップ内で 自身をローカライズする別の手法を
inside a given map.
見つける必要があります
It is common practice to use the onboard sensor
ローカライゼーションの問題を 解決するには
data, along with our global map, to solve the localization
グローバルマップとともに オンボードセンサーデータを使用することが
issue.
一般的な方法です
So with the onboard sensors it is
オンボードセンサー があれば
possible to measure distances to static obstacles,
木 ポール 壁などの 静止物体までの
like trees, poles, or walls.
距離を測定できます
We measure these distances, and the bearing
これらの距離 これらの静止物体
of these static objects in the local
の方位は 車の局所座標系において
coordinate system of our car.
測定します
Now when you're lucky, the same obstacles
運の良いときには オンボードセンサーで
that were observed by the onboard sensors
測定された 同じ障害物が
are also part of the map.
マップにあります
And, of course, the map has its own global coordinate system.
そして 当然マップには 独自のグローバル座標系があります
To estimate where the car is in the map,
マップ内での車の場所を 推定するには
you have to match the observations
観測を マップ情報と
with the map information.
一致させる必要があります
And when you do it correctly, this results
これを正しく行うと 局所の車の座標系と
in a transformation between both coordinate systems--
地図のグローバル座標系の 両方の
the local car coordinate system and the global coordinate
座標系間で 変換が
system of the map.
行われます
This transformation should be as accurate
この変換は できるだけ正確で
as possible-- let's say within a range of 10 centimeters
なければなりません たとえば 10 センチ以下の
or less.
範囲内です
If you are able to estimate this transformation,
この変換を推定できれば ローカライゼーションの
you solve the localization issue.
問題を 解決できます
So after this example, we can summarize.
この例の後 まとめができます
First, localization answers the question
まず ローカライゼーションは
of where the car is in a given map within an accuracy of 10
与えられたマップ内で 10 センチ以下の精度で どこに車がいるのか
centimeters or less.
という質問に答えます
And second, onboard sensors are used
次に オンボードセンサー を使用して
to estimate the transformation between local measurements
局所測定と 与えられたマップの間の
and a given map.
変換を推定します